One man saw it coming.
I, Robot is a action, science fiction film directed by Alex Proyas.
In 2035, where robots are commonplace and abide by the three laws of
robotics, a technophobic cop investigates an apparent suicide.
Suspecting that a robot may be responsible for the death, his
investigation leads him to believe that humanity may be in danger.
Del Spooner, played by Will Smith.
Susan Calvin, played by Bridget Moynahan.
Sonny (voice), played by Alan Tudyk.
Dr. Alfred Lanning, played by James Cromwell.
Lawrence Robertson, played by Bruce Greenwood.
Granny, played by Adrian Ricard.
I, Robot (sometimes stylized as i,Robot) is a 2004 American science fiction action film
directed by Alex Proyas, from a screenplay by Jeff Vintar and Akiva Goldsman.
It stars Will Smith, Bridget Moynahan, Bruce
Greenwood, James Cromwell, and Alan Tudyk.
The film is named after  Isaac Asimov's 1950 short-story collection and incorporates Asimov's
three laws of robotics and several characters, though it is not a direct adaptation.
The film is set in Chicago in 2035.
Highly intelligent robots fill public service positions throughout the world,
operating under the Three Laws of Robotics to keep humans safe.
Detective Del Spooner (Smith) investigates the alleged suicide of U.S.
Robotics founder Alfred Lanning (Cromwell) and believes that a
human-like robot called Sonny (Tudyk) murdered him.
I, Robot was released in the United States on July 16, 2004.
Produced with a budget of $105–120 million, the film grossed $353.1 million worldwide and received mixed
reviews from critics, with praise for the visual effects and acting, but criticism of the plot.
At the 77th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, future, man vs
machine, hero, artificial intelligence (a.i.).
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.